

# Sathiyanarayanan Palani

**Solutions Architect** 

### **About Me**

Hi! I'm Sathiyanarayanan Palani.

**●** I am good at providing solutions for the problems via possibilites in the tech realms as a Solutions Architect. (specialized in 0-1 developmental phase)

Interested in (Entrepreneurship / Problem Solving / POC

Development)

Age 27

Email sathiyanarayanan396@gmail.com

Phone +918072500974

Address 18/26 Rathna Nagar, Alpet,

Manjakuppam, Cuddalore,

Tamil Nadu, India

### **Professional Skills**

Proficiency in Communication
Self-Learning/Problem-Solving
Proof-of-concept development

#### Skills

**Technologies** Category Languages: C, C++, Python, Shell & Batch basics **Operating System:** Linux, windows Communication UART, I2C, SPI Protocols: **Networking Protocols:** TCP/IP, UDP, HTTP, MQTT, SQL SCM: git Git, G Github **Tools and Libraries:** Gtest, FFF, Jenkins, Git, MySQL, OpenCV, Tkinter, paramiko, SCP, pandas, ASTREE, lark - parser, matplotlib, numpy, pyYaml, rich, pytest Web Technologies: C LogExAnWebApp (Fast API, Flask) C ScEqAnWebApp (Fast API, React UI) **DevOps & Deployment:** Jenkins, Docker, kubernetes, Ansible basics 

ansible-LogExAnWebApp-deployment **Machine Learning:** PyPI: P LogExan, ScEqAn, more

# Work Experience (6 years)

#### Semiconductor S/W Product Development Engineer at UST Global, Bangalore

( May, 2022 - Present )

- Responsible for Python Automation test framework, modification, maintenance & Improvement. Handling Development,
   Testing, setting up CICD Nightly using Github actions with custom runners for Python packages, being part of automation telemetry team
- Implementing Serial-Over-Lan using IPMI tool & tee object using Powershell command, with monitoring thread for retrying
  connections during target reboot & Worked on POC for uploading register values to influx DB, using low-latency InfluxDBline-protocol, for Storage, Visualization & analysis. Collecting Performance KPI's from Thermal & Power sub-system via
  Redfish, based on DMTF Docs, using ODATA queries that works on top of REST APIs

#### Senior Engineer at lelektron Technologies, Chennai

(Oct, 2018 - Dec, 2021)

#### Software Validation Engineer at MBRDI, Bangalore (as External)

(Apr, 2019 - Dec, 2021)

- Responsible for writing test scripts for automated validation of measurements in python based on HIL scenarios from DOORS.
- · Responsible for HiL process Automation via SSH using python Libraries like paramiko and SCP.
- Responsible for development of Custom framework and reusable components in Python & Bash for automated test case
  generation using pandas data frames for pre-HIL execution task.
- Responsible for Runtime dynamic analysis of ADAS utility modules in c using ASTREE.
- Responsible for unit testing, L2 testing using Google test framework in c++ based on Scenarios (SIL).

### Python Developer at SAFRAN Aerospace, Bangalore (as External)

(Oct, 2018 - Mar, 2019)

- Responsible for Multi-Display Broadcast over local Network using TCP/IP.
- Responsible for Data Visualization of sensor plots in Aerospace Applications using python & plotly (3d scalar plots).
- Responsible for visualization of volumetric data in the form of normal distribution for the development of algorithm on event classification using Matplotlib.

#### Embedded Software Developer at lelektron Technologies, Chennai

( Jul, 2017 - Sep, 2018 )

- Responsible for Embedded Software unit and functional Testing.
- Responsible for Embedded Software Development of iElektron Security Products.
- Development of multi-branch CI/CD pipeline in Jenkins for Unit Testing with github app integration for events and mail, slack integration for notifications.
- Responsible for development of semi-automated hardware testing platform for Renesas Microcontrollers using Iron-python Renesas APIs

### **Education**

**BE - Electrical and Electronics Engineering** from Anand Institute of Higher Technology, chennai (affiliated to Anna University)

2013 - 2017

- Graduated with a first class in Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
- Final Year project done using OpenCV and Raspberry Pi for Automatic Attendance System using Face Recognition.

HSC from ARLM Matric Higher Secondary School, Cuddalore

2012 - 2013

• Completed with 85%

SSLC from SRV Matric Higher Secondary School, Trichy

2010 - 2011

• Completed with 85%

# **Participations**











## **Proposals**

#### **Element 14 Road Test**

Proposal written on the Test strategy & Test procedure to be followed for testing Xsens MTI-680-DK GNSS/ISS Development Kit.



#### **Cluster Monitoring**

Proposal written on Monitoring clusters, for Visualization of node observability metrics, involved in Intense workloads like Training ML models.

